Empresses in the Palace—the Legend of Zhen Huan
Adapted from the novel by Liu Lian Zi
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Subscription: liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: Unfortunate Love
Perturbed by the thoughts on my mind
no matter how hard I try to sever my love.
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
I could give away my crown for the beauty by my side,
but the wheel of fortune turns weals into woes,
and woes into weals.
No one is the master of their own destiny,
the vicissitudes throughout their life.
For the lovers of all time,
who can break the spell of romance?
Who can break the spell of romance?
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Subscription: liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
You like it, don't you?
My Lady, you seem to be in a good mood today.
It's good to gain favor from both sides.
However, you didn't have to tip off
Consort Fleur directly, My Lady.
We could have stopped Lady Chun ourselves.
If I did that, it would cast suspicion upon me.
It's better to keep myself out of it.
It was Lady Chun's bad luck.
She was in the wrong place at the wrong time.
It is sensible that you alerted Consort Fleur
to Lady Chun's presence, My Lady.
But why did you inform Concubine Sourire as well?
Consort Fleur is in her prime,
but Concubine Sourire is in the ascendant.
Although I side with Consort Fleur,
I can still make use of this opportunity
to do Concubine Sourire a favor.
While it was too late to save Lady Chun
by the time she sent people over,
she will remember today and not make things
too difficult for me when she comes into her prime.
Didn't Concubine Sourire suspect that
you were the one who pushed her at the peony viewing?
Everyone has their suspicions.
But she has to have evidence.
If she does,
would I still be sitting here?
Would I?
When two tigers fight,
the small animal between them needs to find a route of retreat.
Doesn't it?
Grace to Your Majesty.
I had to finish reviewing memorandums.
I hope it's not too late.
It's never late as long as Your Majesty's heart is here.
I will just wait.
That's why I come here regardless of the time.
Your Majesty must be tired after a long day of work.
I didn't send word that I would visit tonight.
How did you know to prepare this?
I long to see Your Majesty every night.
So I have it prepared every night.
I appreciate your thoughts. I also am
thinking of you even if I don't come here.
Your Majesty seems to be in a good mood.
Any good news from the court?
The wars in the southwest.
Your brother and nephew accomplished a great feat.
I wish to reward your brother the first-order hereditary chieftaincy.
Since your father Nian Xialing already holds a first-order title,
He will now be known as the Imperial Marshal.
Your brother's previous title of nobility
will be granted to his second son Nian Fu.
I will also grant your mother the second noble rank.
What do you think?
I thank Your Majesty.
I am also considering promoting
Concubine Souririe's father
as she is deeply saddened by Noble Lady Chun's death.
This could be a way to relieve her sorrow.
But wasn't her father disrespectful to Your Majesty?
I have punished him for that.
If you disagree,
I will keep him in the Censorate
but promote him as the Imperial Censor [upper fourth rank].
How about that?
I dare not disagree with Your Majesty's decree.
As long as Concubine Sourire is happy.
I appreciate your understanding.
You have been holding the rank Consort for years.
I plan to grant you a higher rank after the Dragon Boat Festival.
I only wish to attend Your Majesty every day.
I care nothing about the ranks.
Grace and peace to Your Majesty.
Rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Grace and peace to Consort Fleur.
Rise.
I thank Your Highness.
Why is everyone so courteous today ?
We heard that His Majesty is going to promote you.
As your family, we wish to congratulate you.
As the Empress, only Your Majesty is greeted like that.
I've never expected to be greeted the same way.
What does Your Highness mean by that?
When His Majesty was still a lord, and you were
promoted from his Lord Consort to primary wife,
his Lord Concubines must have congratulated you just like this.
That's very smart of you to place yourself in my shoes.
How can I compare to Your Majesty who's
not only smart but blessed by Heaven?
Your Majesty always shows understanding of His Majesty.
I wonder what rank His Majesty will grant me.
There is Noble Consort above Consort
and Imperial Noble Consort above Noble Consort.
I presume His Majesty's will promote you in this order.
That's incorrect, Your Majesty.
Above the Imperial Noble Consort,
there is the Empress.
Oh,
you mean, you are interested in my throne?
Your Majesty must not worry.
It's just that
I heard the Imperial Noble Consort is like a second Empress.
Imperial Consort Donggo of Emperor Shunzhi
did not leave Empress Borjigin "a place to stand" in the palace.
I'm sure you are well-versed in history.
But however distinguished an Imperial Noble Consort is,
she is second to the Empress.
The Empress is the Empress after all.
An emperor may have an Imperial Noble Consort,
but only the Empress is "the Mother of the Nation".
Although Donggo was conferred
the title of Empress posthumously,
she never ruled as an Empress.
"You cannot be addressed by a name that is not yours."
You should wisely understand the
bounds of duty and appropriateness.
You are like "the wind whistling over level ground."
I was just asking out of curiosity
and Your Majesty has been discoursing on titles and names.
I wonder if anyone would think
Your Majesty sees an Imperial Noble Consort
as a nemesis the way Empress Borjigin did.
It is the Empress's duty to
educate the concubines and uphold discipline.
I hope my words will assist you managing the palace
with virtue and reason after your promotion.
I appreciate Your Majesty's advice.
If I have the blessing to be promoted,
I will fulfill my role and help execute Your Majesty's
duties of palace management.
Your Majesty will have more time to yourself.
You've been in low spirits since Lady Chun's passing.
I'm relieved to see that you have come out today.
Meizhuang has visited me a lot, but she
hasn't fully recovered from the disease.
Attendant An's cough keeps her in.
Her Highness Consort Estime has been visiting me quite often.
That raised my spirits.
Consort Estime has a kind heart.
I sent you a white cockatoo to keep you company.
Do you like him?
I do. He makes funny sounds.
Your Majesty,
General Longkodo is here.
Allow me to take my leave.
- Show him in.
- Yes.
Peace to Your Majesty.
Uncle Longkodo.
Please rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Have a seat.
Uncle, is there something urgent
that brings you to the palace today?
Your Majesty, it was brought to my notice that Nian
Gengyao's residence is under massive reconstruction.
He demolished hundreds of neighboring
citizen's homes to build onto his gardens.
His renovated residence will have the scale of a State Prince
which oversteps the bounds of propriety.
I have just rewarded him.
His extravagance is to exhibit his honor.
I understand.
But Nian Gengyao has made thousands
homeless and they seek shelter on the street.
If this can happen in Your Majesty's capital,
I wonder if in Qinghai Province, Great General Nian
will have a more palatial residence than a State Prince.
He will not, Uncle Longkodo.
Although Nian Gengyao has a lot of pride in himself,
he knows the bounds of propriety.
Your Majesty ...
I understand you and Nian Gengyao are very different.
He is merely a servant of the imperial family
while you are my family.
In my court you are his only equal.
I hope you will continue giving me your observations
so Nian Gengyao will not forget his boundaries.
I will eternally remember Your Majesty's heavenly grace.
I heard Her Majesty the Empress Dowager
was not feeling well.
I hope Her Majesty has been feeling better.
I wonder if I can pay my respects to Her Majesty.
Thank you, Uncle Longkodo.
Imperial Mother is fatigued due to the illness.
Otherwise she would welcome seeing you.
Since the imperial doctors advised her to rest,
I’m afraid she can't see you today.
You should come visit her when she feels better.
Allow me to take my leave, Your Majesty.
Look at you!
You are getting so much better at needlework!
The flowers look vividly alive.
You're teasing me, Estime.
You know I’m not good at needlework.
I didn't start practicing it until I entered the palace.
I can see the motherly love you stitch into it.
That’s better than anything.
My Lady, Your Highness,
the Palace of Great Benevolence informs us that
Her Majesty is having a severe migraine attack.
Her Majesty requests all available
concubines attend to her throughout the night.
Who is attending to Her Majesty now?
Consort Fleur is with His Majesty.
Lady Fuca is in recovery from her miscarriage.
Lady Vertu and Attendant An have not returned to full health.
Consort Astuce and Attendant Joie are in attendance.
I see, I will go immediately.
I should go with you.
It's not as convenient for you.
Her Majesty hardly ever requests attendance by the concubines.
I would worry about her if I didn't go.
I shall go with you.
All right.
Your Majesty.
Your Majesty, please hold on a little longer.
Your Majesty, hold on.
Autumn.
Haven't the imperial doctors visited?
Not yet.
Why were the doctors not called in
when Her Majesty began feeling unwell?
I did send for the doctors.
But all the doctors on duty are absent.
How can that be?
I went to the Infirmary myself
and there were two doctors, but they
solely serve the Empress Dowager.
All the other doctors had been
summoned by Great General Nian.
How… How could this happened?
It was reported at noon that General Nian's
wife suddenly fell ill,
and they took all the doctors away
to personally serve his wife.
How could they do that?
That is absurd!
Nothing could be more absurd!
The Empress is the center of the harem,
but she can't even find a doctor!
And all the doctors are serving an official!
Send someone to bring the doctors here immediately!
I have, Your Highness.
But General Nian said that his wife's condition is grave.
They couldn't spare a single doctor.
He told the messengers that the doctors would
never return if his wife's condition worsened.
Did you inform His Majesty?
Her Majesty would not let me.
And ...
His Majesty is with Consort Fleur tonight.
He might not want to come.
Her Majesty is in severe pain.
How can you not report to His Majesty?
I…
Stop standing there!
Go!
Autumn …
Don’t go …
It's late ... His Majesty needs to rest …
His Majesty has to get up early for court.
But we have to call in the doctors.
They get called in by the Nians from time to time.
And the palace gates have been locked,
Let's not make any trouble.
Tomorrow morning ...
they will be back.
Your Majesty…
That’s enough. I said no.
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Your Highness.
The Empress was sick again last night.
She had a bad migraine all night.
For the entire night?
I will go see her earlier than usual.
My brother has gone too far this time.
Taking all the doctors away!
What if His Majesty needed to see them?
Tell him to treat the doctors nicely and send them back soon.
Yes, Your Highness.
Hold on.
Come check His Majesty's breakfast with me.
His Majesty likes the pickled cucumber.
Place it in front of him.
Yes.
Hold on.
His Majesty took only a bite of the baozi.
He's had too much of it recently.
Put it further away.
Your Highness.
The Household Department requests an audience.
What brings them here so early?
Send them in.
Yes, Your Highness.
Peace to Your Highness.
Isn’t that the robe for Imperial Noble Consort?
Who ordered you to send that?
Our superior told us to deliver it.
Is this by His Majesty’s decree?
We don’t know, Your Highness.
Who would dare to send this if it wasn't His Majesty’s decree?
Thank you for delivering it here.
Mr. Zhou will give you the reward.
- I thank Your Highness.
- Yes.
This way please.
Warmest congratulations to Your Imperial Highness.
Your Majesty, I have one matter to report.
Yes.
I heard that no imperial doctor was available last night
when Her Majesty was having a severe migraine attack.
Her Majesty is the mother of the nation.
The doctors' would be derelict of duty if they failed to
provide timely treatment for Her Majesty.
But if someone emptied the
Imperial Infirmary for selfish interest
and caused delay in Her Majesty's treatment,
they must be severely punished.
Your Majesty,
My wife suffered an emergency at noon yesterday.
I hastily sent for the imperial doctors on duty.
I could never have expected Her Majesty
would have a migraine attack.
It was my lack of consideration.
I was too concerned about my wife.
I beg for Your Majesty’s forgiveness.
Rise.
I thank Your Majesty.
Until your arm injury is completely recovered,
I am permitting imperial doctors to visit your family residence.
For a loving couple like you and your wife,
I understand your concern for her in an emergency.
Has her emergency been relieved?
I thank Your Majesty for asking.
She’s much better this morning.
I have sent the imperial doctors back to the Palace.
Although it was an urgent situation,
you will need to be more thoughtful in the future.
Yes.
There should always be a doctor in
the harem in case of an internal emergency.
I recognize my fault.
I dare not act so recklessly in the future.
You all are officials at court
but husbands at home.
The state affairs matter to you,
and so do your families.
Just like General Nian,
you must be the pillars of the nation
and the backbone of your families.
Yes, Your Majesty.
You were here early this morning, and now have come again.
You must be careful of your own health.
Please don’t worry about me, Your Majesty.
I’m all right. I just want to be here for Your Majesty.
Don't worry, the imperial doctors have visited.
This was taken so seriously that an
official reported it to His Majesty.
But I heard His Majesty didn’t get angry
and praised General Nian instead.
It’s a chronic illness. It doesn’t matter.
Has His Majesty visited Your Majesty?
He came here after court and stayed until I took the medicine.
His Majesty is busy with state affairs.
I don’t wish to be a bother.
His Majesty is excessively biased towards the Nians.
I heard that the Household Department sent the robe
for Imperial Noble Consort to the Palace of Earthly Honor.
Dr Wen.
Peace to Your Highness.
You must be busy now that you
are in charge of treating the plague.
His Majesty commended this task to me.
I must put forth my best effort.
There's one thing I wish to ask you.
All the imperial doctors were summoned
by General Nian last night
and no one was on duty in the infirmary.
How many doctors are usually on duty at night?
The entire Imperial Infirmary has been unsettled
since the incident concerns Her Majesty's health.
I asked my colleagues and they told me that
only Dr. Li and Dr. Zhang went to the Nians'.
Dr. Chen and Dr. Zhao stayed in the palace.
But when Jiang Fuhai came to the infirmary for the herbs
and saw Dr. Li and Dr. Zhang were not there,
he said since Lady Fuca is recovering from
her miscarriage and Your Highness is pregnant,
the most respected doctors must stay in the palace.
So he sent Dr. Chen and Dr. Zhao to the
Nians and Dr. Li and Dr. Zhang returned.
Nian Gengyao was in urgent need of doctors.
Yet he agreed to return Dr. Li and Dr. Zhang -
the most respected doctors.
What about the other imperial doctors?
Would they be able to enter the palace
if they were called for at night?
Although the palace gates are locked at night,
they would be permitted to enter if summoned by Her Majesty.
But that would be quite disturbing to the harem.
Understood.
Thank you, Dr. Wen.
I haven't served Your Highness
while you are pregnant.
How is everything?
All is well. Dr. Zhang is very experienced.
I'm glad to hear that.
I will pay my respects to Your Highness another day.
My Lady, do you have doubts over what happened last night?
I'm just speculating.
Her Majesty is always self-restrained and courteous.
Could it be that she did not want to
disturb the palace over her illness?
If she wished that no one would know,
she wouldn't summon the concubines
to take turns attending her.
Whether it was courteous self-restraint or a
case of "the drinker's intention is not in the cup",
we have to "push the boat along the current"
since we are on the same boat as Her Majesty.
What are you reading?
I picked up "The Commentary of Zuo"
from Your Majesty's desk.
The more I read, the more intrigued I am.
Which passage are you on?
Earl Zhuang Overcame Duan in Yan City.
That's an old chestnut.
Why are you interested in that?
Although it's an old story, this cautionary tale is thought provoking.
Earl Zhuang's mother wished to replace him with his younger brother Duan.
Zhuang indulged Duan's wrongdoing several times;
then, once Duan provoked public anger, he killed him.
I believe, as a monarch, Earl Zhuang was smart to create a reason to remove him.
I've received many memorandums recently denouncing
Nian Gengyao's obtrusively insolent manner.
Your Majesty, I know nothing about state affairs.
I'm just fond of this story.
If you say so, I do feel this is a well-written tale.
It's worth a read.
There is one sentence that captured my mind.
Which is?
I would like Your Majesty to take a guess.
Let's see if we share the same mind.
"The injustice one does unto others will destroy oneself."
Huan Huan knows my heart.
His Majesty's decree.
To Consort Fleur.
Your Majesty.
By the grace of Heaven, His Majesty decrees
“Consort Fleur from the distinguished Nian family
upholds honor and solemnity.”
"At Her Majesty the Empress Dowager’s benevolent
behest, I hereby grant her the title of Noble Consort."
This is His Majesty’s edict.
Sir, did you wrongly declaim His Majesty's decree?
Does His Majesty promote me just to Noble Consort?
Your Highness, the decree was written by His Majesty.
There is no mistake.
I congratulate Your Noble Highness.
But the Household Department has
presented me the robe for an Imperial Noble Consort.
Oh, it was used by Imperial Noble Consort Quehui of the prior emperor.
His Majesty said he hasn't had an
Imperial Noble Consort yet.
So the robe has been kept
as a reference for the future Imperial Noble Consort.
It was delivered by accident.
Your Highness will need to send it back.
Song Zhi.
Yes.
Return the robe.
Your Highness.
Your Highness is His Majesty's first Noble Consort.
And the only Noble Consort.
With such a prestigious honor,
Does Your Highness need to worry about being
promoted to Imperial Noble Consort?
Besides, Your Highness's family has
accomplished extraordinary military feats
and Your Highness is high in His Majesty's favor,
entrusted with the authority to assist in palace management.
With everything going well,
Your Highness will have a justifiable
promotion when you have an imperial heir.
Thank you for your kind words, sir.
I shall take my leave if Your Highness allows.
I congratulate Your Noble Highness.
You may leave now.
There will be time to congratulate me
after the promotion ceremony.
Yes.
Your Noble Highness.
His Majesty has to consider Her Majesty's status.
Therefore ...
It was just my wishful thinking.
Meizhuang.
I have some good Biluochun tea.
It calms the mind and reduces internal Heat.
Here, have some tea.
Consort Fleur ...
It's Noble Consort Fleur.
Noble Consort Fleur.
Yes.
I only resent that I don't have such
a father and a brother
to fight on the battlefield.
Isn't she lucky?
Don't be angry, Meizhuang.
Noble Consort Fleur is now in a prime position.
It reminds me of Noble Consort Wenxi of Emperor Kangxi.
Noble Consort Wenxi?
Her Noble Highness is the mother of State Prince Dun,
daughter of General Ebilun,
and younger sister of Empress Xiaozhaoren.
General Ebilun was a supporter of regent Oboi
who amassed too much power.
Emperor Kangxi was very generous but did not tolerate him.
We needn't worry about Nian Gengyao, who shows
such imperious conceit over his unrivaled power.
I have also heard that Nian Gengyao
has become aggressive and domineering.
He aroused controversy in court.
But His Majesty just laughed it off
and treated Nian with greater generosity.
If an ulcer festers then there is a reason to eliminate it.
The more it festers, the more easily
we can remove it at the root.
All we need to do is wait.
But Meizhuang, recently you have been cold
and distant towards His Majesty.
Am I supposed to fawn over him for his favor?
I am just someone he "waves in and waves out".
You are more susceptible to
their tormenting if you lose His Majesty's favor.
You experienced it.
I need not remind you about that.
Consort Fleur is prominently in favor.
The nights you attend to His Majesty are more
than double the other concubines combined.
His Majesty undoubtedly holds you in his highest esteem.
Your Majesty always banters with me.
His Majesty enjoys my company.
It's an honor to serve His Majesty so frequently.
I'm happy that His Majesty is pleased with your service.
But since you are His Majesty's most favored concubine,
I hope you will bring an imperial heir to the family soon.
That's true.
But if it's just a princess,
it's not worth the effort.
I do not agree, Consort Astuce.
If it's a smart prince,
his mother will certainly gain more favor from His Majesty.
But if it's a dumb prince,
neither the mother nor the son
will be favored by His Majesty.
How dare you ...
That's enough.
A child must be carefully taught regardless of their aptitude.
Your priority is to have a healthy child.
Speaking of which, I wish you all
could be as blessed as Concubine Sourire.
Whether I have a prince or princess,
I will love them just the same.
I'll be happy if my child is as clever as Princess Wenyi.
Consort Astuce, did you hear that?
Even Concubine Sourire knows that Princess Wenyi
is much more clever than the Third Prince.
Your Highness,
I didn't mean anything like that.
Then what did you mean?
Not long after you got pregnant,
Lady Fuca lost her child, and is unable to serve His Majesty.
This gave you a chance to rise in His Majesty's favor
and now you are showing off your luck.
You overcame Lady Fuca like "Fire overcomes Wood."
And now you dare to slander the Third Prince?
Enough!
Stop talking nonsense.
What was wrong with you?
You hold a distinguished title as the mother of the Third Prince.
Why did you have to argue with the other concubines?
How much gossip will this arouse?
I didn't want to argue with Concubine Sourire.
But I'm the mother of the Third Prince.
I had to speak for him.
You gave birth to him and I have been
caring for him as his Imperial Mother.
I care about him as much as you do.
I know I'm getting old.
And His Majesty no longer favors me.
I don't really mind that,
But the Third Prince cannot lose favor as the eldest prince.
You are one of the concubines
who have served His Majesty the longest.
How could His Majesty not care for you?
The Third Prince is the only adult son of His Majesty.
Concubine Sourire's child stands no chance of catching up to him.
However,
Concubine Sourire is now in high favor,
and she has the same family banners as yours.
It's quite possible that her child will hold
a status equal to the third prince's.
Your Majesty ...
Emperor Shunzhi determined that his
newborn son would be the crown prince.
But don't worry.
If His Majesty intends to follow suit,
I will certainly dissuade His Majesty.
The fourth prince of Emperor Shunzhi ...
Didn't he die when he was still an infant?
Indeed. What a poor child.
Had his mother known that he would die so soon,
why would she give birth to him?
Aiya ... Amitabha Buddha.
I shouldn't have said such sinful words.
Peace to Your Highness.
Your Highness ...
What's the matter?
I do not wish to disturb Your Highness.
But Your Highness must not stand under the oleander tree.
Why not?
The sap and pollen of the tree are poisonous.
Your Highness must be careful to not touch them.
Really?
Yes, Your Highness.
Fortunately, there are no oleander trees
near the Palace of Pearl Jade.
Otherwise, they would be troublesome for Sourire's pregnancy.
Why's that?
Oleander can damage Heart Qi and cause miscarriages.
In my hometown,
all pregnant women would stay away from it.
My lady,
you need to pay respects to Her Majesty.
You should go now so you won't be late.
I bid Your Highness goodbye.
Look, my waist got even bigger.
I look so round.
Sit down, Sourire.
I don't think you look bigger around.
Your child is not even four months old.
You might not be able to notice,
but I know how much bigger my little child has grown.
It's summer already.
The phoenix flowers are blooming.
I remember Chun'er ...
She was so fond of the phoenix flowers.
I have offered incense in the Baohua Hall for Lady Chun.
Had I not been pregnant,
I would have gone myself to burn incense for her,
which could give me a blessing to avenge her.
You are pregnant.
It's not good for your child to hear something about "revenge".
You are not as careful as you sound.
You don't have to visit me often when your throat isn't cured.
The wind outside could aggravate your condition.
That doesn't matter.
Talking to you alleviates some of my boredom.
These days I have been feeling unwell from the pressure on my chest.
Hasn't Doctor Zhang prescribed you the cassia twig soup?
The cassia twig is warm in nature and can ease your breathing.
It is the best for your chest tightness.
I drink it every day but don't feel any better.
My Lady, Consort Astuce sent someone here.
It's unusual for her to do so.
Yes.
Let her in.
Peace and grace to Concubine Sourire and Attendant An.
You may rise.
Yes, Your Highness.
Consort Astuce sends this chestnut cake that she made herself.
Please enjoy, Your Highness.
Please give my thanks to her.
Allow me to take my leave.
Now I feel hungry.
Lingrong, have some.
The Palace of Earthly Honor makes the best pastry.
Let's see how these from the palace of Consort Astuce compare .
Wait.
You can't eat it.
Why?
There's something wrong with the pastry.
Chestnuts should be sweet.
But it smells bitter.
Put it down, Sourire.
The pastry is mixed with the pollen and juice of oleanders.
This...
Oleander is cold in nature and poisonous.
It removes blood stasis and relieves pain.
But everyone knows that you are drinking the cassia twig soup.
If the oleander combines with the cassia twig,
the effect doubles.
It could impose fatal damage to your child.
According to that maid,
these are made by Consort Astuce herself.
Yes.
I understand it now.
She must be jealous of your favor and your child
and concocted this evil plan!
I'll go tell His Majesty about it.
Wait, Sourire.
Sit down first, please.
If His Majesty knows about it,
he will vent his anger on Consort Astuce.
But the third prince is also the eldest grandson of Her Majesty.
Although she won't care too much about Consort Astuce,
she will definitely protect her grandson.
As the the eldest son of His Majesty,
he might take the throne one day,
and you will become his first enemy.
At that time, what could you do?
But I have to do something about it.
I'll decide what to do after Dr. Zhang examines the pastry.
Vermilion, take it.
Yes.
Hurry.
Apple, has Concubine Sourire accepted the pastry?
Yes.
But I couldn't stay long,
so I didn't see if she has eaten it or not.
It can't be.
The effect should have been immediate.
Could it be that I didn't put in enough oleander?
Don't worry, Your Highness. Let's wait.
Peace to Consort Astuce.
You may rise.
Your Highness, Her Majesty asks you to go see her now.
But Her Majesty usually takes a nap at this time.
Why would she call me?
Her Majesty must have something urgent to tell you.
Please, Your Highness.
Peace and Grace to Your Majesty.
Why didn't you take a nap today?
And where are your maids?
Kneel down.
Your Majesty...
Translators: The Magpie Bridge Brigade 鹊桥小队翻译组
Subscription: liberapay.com/ZHZSubbers
Twitter/FB/IG @BrigadeMagpie 公众号/微博: 鹊桥小队翻译组
Theme: The Lonely Phoenix
[phoenix is the symbol of an empress]
I dimly recall the colorful blooms in every summer.
They are as distant as the autumn moon in the water.
He loved me with a volatile heart.
And before I knew it, we fell apart.
Behind me are the promises and longing.
Before me lie the flute and the zither.
I loved you with my body and soul
But you hurt me from head to toe.
My wish ran athwart
and I ended up a fool of my destiny.
My love was the wind-swept flowers from a tree.
A plum bloomed in winter hoping for a fruitful summer.
But the irresistible winds of destiny destroyed her wish.
You can hear the flapping of a phoenix
but you will never see it.
What you see is the falling leaves from the phoenix tree.
The falling leaves from the phoenix tree.